# YUNZHE WANG

784 Columbus Ave, New York, NY

(213) - 421 - 9274 | yw3737@columbia.edu | Home Page: yunzhew.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

With an interdisciplinary passion for Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Science, I seek to answer: "What is intelligence and how should we recreate it?" I envision General AI emerging in the next 5-10 years, and I want its primary purpose to be assisting and augmenting human capabilities in a trustworthy manner. Keywords below best encapsulates my interests:

Self-supervised Learning, Few-Shot Learning, Multi-Modality, Cognitive AI, Autonomous Intelligence, Multi-Agent System AI Security, Robustness, Fairness, Human-AI Interaction and Collaboration, Augmented Intelligence, Assistive Technologies

#### **EDUCATION**

**Columbia University** (GPA: 3.96/4.00)

M.S. Computer Science, Machine Learning Track + Advanced Research

Aug 2021 - May 2023

New York, NY

**University of Southern California** (GPA: 3.84/4.00)

B.S. Computational Neuroscience

B.A. Applied Mathematics Minor Computer Science Los Angeles, CA Aug 2017 - May 2021

**Relevant Coursework:** Machine Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Applied Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics, Cognitive Neuroscience, Sensation and Perception, Neurobiology, Brain Architecture, Cellular and Molecular Neuroscience, Statistics, Probability Theory, Numerical Methods, Calculus, Optimization, Computer Networks, Social Networks, Databases, Data Structure, Algorithm Analysis, Advanced Algorithms

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Bubble Group, Inc. - A leader in the Low-Code/No-Code (LCNC) tech domain

New York, NY Jul 2023 - Present

- Software Engineer (Generative AI)
- Conducted Generative AI research and development in text-to-web-application generation, creating an AI Copilot.
- Initiated and led the LLM-Agent Approach, enabling generating stylistic and responsive websites directly from natural language. Emphasized scalability, cost-efficiency, and time.
- Formulated a Vision Reward Model based on DINOv2, Falcon40B LLM-tuning, applied VQ-Diffusion for Layout Generation.

#### **Creative Machines Lab at Columbia University**

Student Researcher

New York, NY Sep 2021 - May 2023

• Machine Learning and Robotics research with Prof. Hod Lipson

#### Project: Conversational Face Robot

- Collaborated on creating a conversational face robot with human-like lip-sync and co-expressive facial dynamics.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
  - o Designed a speech-driven talking face generation model, enhancing the robot with verbal interaction capabilities.
  - o Utilized self-supervised learning, achieving model robustness for varied speakers and languages with limited data.
  - o Utilized GAN, LSTM, and Multi-Modal Transformer architectures, modalities in speech, videos, and 3D landmarks.

#### Project: Robot Morphology Transfer Learning

- Developed a 12-DOF quadruped robot capable of self-morphology identification and realtime trajectory optimization.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
  - Developed a classifier capable of identifying 12-DOF robot morphologies from motion dynamics, enabled trajectory optimization for robot with unseen morphologies.
  - o Utilized Transfer Learning and Multi-Task Learning; Data modalities in time-series (IMU) and point cloud.

# Cognitive Architecture Lab at USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Los Angeles, CA Feb 2020 - Aug 2021

Student Researcher

- Cognitive Architecture and Human-AI Collaboration research with Prof. Paul Rosenbloom and Dr. Volkan Ustun.
- Developed a real-time routing decision-augmenting framework for Urban Search-and-Rescue tasks, leveraging Graph Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, and Unsupervised Learning to enhance Human-AI collaboration.
- Software development for the Graphical Model aspects of the (Py)Sigma Cognitive Architecture.

#### **Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Science**

Research Internship

Beijing, China May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Natural Language Processing Research mentored by Prof. Cungen Cao, focused on Knowledge Extraction.
- Created a rule-based system for Chinese Part-of-Speech tagging optimization, integrating data mining and pattern matching to boost model accuracy and efficiency.

| PUBLICATIONS   |             |
|--|-------------|
| Efficient Transfer Learning Across Robot Morphologies Y. Hu, Y. Wang, R. Liu, Z. Shen, H. Lipson. Submitted to International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA 2024)   | 2022 - 2023 |
| Lip Synchronization for Animatronic Robot Face Y. Hu, Yu. Wang, B. Chen, Yi. Wang, J. Lin, H. Lipson. In Submission to Science Robotics  | 2021 - 2023 |
| Human-Robot Facial Co-expression Y. Hu, B. Chen, J. Lin, <u>Yu. Wang</u> , Yi. Wang, H. Lipson. Science Robotics (From Revision)   | 2021 - 2023 |
| Route Optimization in Service of a Search and Rescue Artificial Social Intelligence Agent Y. Wang, N. Gurney, J. Zhou, D. Pynadath, V. Ustun.  Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence 2021 Fall Symposium Series (AAAI FSS 2021) | 2020 - 2021 |
| TEACHING   |             |
| Applied Computer Vision (Teaching Assistant)   | Spring 2023 |
| Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)   | Fall 2022   |
| Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)   | Summer 2022 |

#### **AWARDS**

USC Graduate with Distinction (Magna Cum Laude)

Academic Achievement Award, University of Southern California

Dean's List, all semesters, University of Southern California

American Mathematical Contest 12 (top 5%), Mathematical Association of America

#### **PROJECTS**

| Medium Writer on AI Topics                     | bit.ly/medium-yunzhe    | 2023 |
|--|-------------------------|------|
| Interactive Visualization of 1.7M Arxiv Papers | bit.ly/arxiv-embed-viz  | 2023 |
| Audio-Visual Speaker Diarization               | bit.ly/syncnet-spk      | 2023 |
| Unsupervised Neural Machine Translation        | bit.ly/unmt-survey      | 2022 |
| Autonomous Car-Racing Game Agent in Unity      | bit.ly/auto-drive-agent | 2021 |
| •  | 3,                      | -    |

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming and Development:** Python, C++, SQL, JavaScript/TypeScript, Git, LaTeX, Web Development, Web Scraping AI and Machine Learning: PyTorch, scikit-learn, Tensor Programming, Data Visualization, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Sequence Modeling, Prompt Engineering, Large Language Model

Others: Bilingual in English and Chinese, Photography, Drawing, Culinary